MICHELLE DANG

mbdang@edu.uwaterloo.ca michelledang.github.io linkedin.com/in/dang-michelle 905-464-8126

Summary of Qualifications

Detail oriented self-starter with demonstrated ability to learn quickly through courseware and side projects.

Able to work well independently and collaboratively as an enthusiastic team member.

Experience With

React | Ember | JS | TS | HTML | CSS C/C++ | Java | Python | GraphQL Git | Linux | Android Studio | Bash

Relevant Courses

User Interfaces

Algorithms

Data Structures and Data Mgmt

Human Computer Interaction

Object Oriented Software Development

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science, 2021

University of Waterloo Sept 2016 - Present

High School Diploma + Ontario French Immersion Certificate

M.M. Robinson High School 2012-2016

Awards/Achievements

President's Scholarship of Distinction, 2017

University of Waterloo

Miriam Collins Leadership Award, 2016

Canadian Federation of University Women's Club

Interests/Hobbies

Music

(playing instruments, making playlists, attending concerts)

Comedy

(tv shows, film, podcasts, stand-up)

Photography

Work Experience

LinkedIn

UI Engineer Intern

Sunnyvale, CA Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

- Designed an internal tool responsible for configuring taxes that affect all of LinkedIn's online transactions.
- Implemented the UI and mid-tier APIs to support the tool.
- Project was designed with Figma and developed using Ember, JavaScript, Java and Scala.

New York, NY SeatGeek

Software Engineering Intern

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Simplified SeatGeek's internal search engine by replacing categorical search with a single input that handles all guery types.
- Redesigned the search page and search results layout using Sketch to develop mock designs while getting feedback from stakeholders.
- Project was developed using React, TypeScript, GraphQL, Redux and Node.

Bellevue. WA Microsoft Sept 2018 - Dec 2018

Software Engineering Intern

- Developed an activity timeline displaying a user's email, deal and meeting history with a contact in Outlook Customer Manager.
- Implemented contact search UI to allow users to include new contacts in existing deals.
- Both features were created using React, TypeScript and C#.

Microsoft

Software Engineering Intern

Redmond, WA

Jan 2018 - Apr 2018

- Collaborated with PMs and designers to plan feedback collection in Office Business Center and Outlook Customer Manager using Office Customer Voice SDK and APIs.
- Implemented user-initiated feedback feature in C# middle-tier and HTML/CSS/Javascript front-end.
- Feedback collected with my feature improved the development cycle by allowing bug tracking and direct communication with customers.

Redmond, WA Microsoft

Explore Intern

May 2017 - Aug 2017

- Created customer scenarios and designed ux/wireframes for third party integrations in Microsoft's Business Center website in a Program Manager role (two months).
- Prototyped third-party integration using .NET framework, C# and HTML/CSS in a Software Engineering role (two months).
- Completed OAuth 2.0 log-in and data collection into Business Center from thirdparty REST APIs.

Projects (available on Github)

- Personal Website HTML/CSS
- Tetris C++

- Tip Calculator Android App Java
- Ice Skating Lap Timer Arduino